Eliza M. Janus

emj4em@virginia.edu | 540.903.8216 | Richmond, Virginia https://elizajanus.github.io/portfolio/ | https://linkedin.com/in/elizamariejanus

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Creative and inquisitive problem-solver with a knack for troubleshooting and a passion for data. Experience in eCommerce and B2B eProcurement technology, software integrations, software support, search engine optimization, and website analytics. Full stack JavaScript developer excited for a lifelong career in software development.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Node.js, Express, AWS (Lambda, EC2, API Gateway, SNS, RDS), REST API development, JavaScript, React, Mocha, Chai, jQuery, Github, MongoDB, MySQL, Firebase, socket.io, PM2, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Media Queries, JSON, EDI, AJAX, the command line, computer science fundamentals, SEO, Adobe Analytics, Google Analytics, Perl. Training in personal learning queue: Python, Java, C#

PROJECTS

MaraGoal https://maragoal.herokuapp.com/

- Full stack marathon training web application using MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js
- Developed in about 2 weeks
- Features include user authentication, calendar with personalized training schedule, running diary, and group chat
- Personally responsible for real-time group chat feature with socket.io, as well as troubleshooting throughout the application

Twin Peaks Clicky Game https://react-clicky-twin-peaks.herokuapp.com/

- Front end web application built with React
- Developed in 1 day
- User clicks on array of Twin Peaks characters that shuffle after each click. If a character is clicked more than once, the score is reset

Mongo Scraper https://mongoscraper5.herokuapp.com/

- Full stack Node.js application using Express, MongoDB/Mongoose, Cheerio, and Bootstrap
- Developed in about 3 days
- Scrapes and displays article title, summary, and link from https://www.theonion.com/c/news-in-brief/
- Option to save articles to a "Saved" page, delete from "Saved," add a note (notes functionality unfinished)

Friend Finder https://friend-finder21.herokuapp.com/

- Node application using Express and Bootstrap
- Developed in about 3 days
- User fills out a personality survey and is matched with a new friend based on survey results

EXPERIENCE

Social Auto Transport at StartupVA

7/2018-present

Node.js Developer

- Independently developing a REST API with Node.js, Sequelize, MySQL on AWS RDS, and Express on AWS EC2. TDD with Mocha/Chai.
- Built a prototype front-end React /Node.js application that utilizes a third party API to create "moves" (various series of A-B car rides) based on specifications.
- Set up AWS integration using webhooks, API Gateway, Lambda, VPC, Sequelize/MySQL, and SNS.

VCU Parkinson's and Movement Disorders Center

6/2017-7/2018

Administrative Assistant, Project Coordinator, and Web Producer

- Event, sponsorship, and outreach coordinator. Project coordinator for the Movin' & Shakin' 5K fundraiser. Responsible for coordinating sponsorships and donations, advertising education and awareness events, interfacing with the patient community.
- Independently transferred PMDC website from FTP server to T4 CMS. Maintained website content in T4.

PunchOut2Go, Inc.

12/2016-6/2017

Software Integrations Project Manager

- Manager of PunchOut2Go's largest eProcurement software implementation project to date.
- Provided technical support for PunchOut2Go clients, performed project status presentations for clients. Configured integrations involving procurement platforms including SAP/Ariba, Coupa, and Jaggaer.

Delivery Agent, Inc.

1/2016-12/2016

eCommerce Assistant and Web Operations

- Maintained webstore content on custom CMS, prepared and executed promotional marketing campaigns. Troubleshot and resolved, or managed resolution of, technical issues on webstores.
- Tracked eCommerce metrics and ran reports for analysis, merchandised product based on sales metrics. Optimized links for SEO performance.

EDUCATION

University of Richmond, Richmond, Virginia

1/2018-7/2018

University of Richmond Coding Boot Camp – Full Stack Web Developer Certification An intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned included Node.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Express, React, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, and Handlebars.

University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia

1/2013-6/2015

Bachelor of Arts, Music, Class of 2015

Concentration in music composition, significant coursework in computer music composition.